Cid Corman Letters
Cid Corman Letters
1950-1971
Corman, Cid
.75 linear ft
Mostly family correspondence, the bulk of which was generated during Corman’s sojourn in Japan during the 1950s.
149342
Biographical History
Cid Corman was a Boston-born poet, editor and translator. He was owner of the Origin Press and editor and publisher of Origin magazine.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Cid Corman Letters contain mostly family correspondence and some outgoing correspondence to his friends. The letters provide a view both of Cid Corman's private life and his growth as a poet. In addition, these letters illuminate the financial hardships he experienced as editor of Origin, his poetry magazine. While living in Kyoto, Japan during the early 1950s, Corman traveled much of the time yet he continued to have close ties with his family, especially his brother Leonard. While in Kyoto, he published Sun Rock Man and Hearth, among other works.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radicalism; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Corman, Cid; Creeley, Robert, 1926-; Eigner, Larry, 1927-; Enslin, Ted; Fang, Achilles; Taggart, John, 1942-; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Origin; American poetry -- 20th century.; Bohemianism, United States; Literature, Experimental; Poets, American; Letters (correspondence); Postcards.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase.
Inventory
- Family correspondence
  - Corman, Shizumi (wife), undated (Box 1)
  - Corman, Abraham (father), 1962-1968 (Box 1)
  - Corman, Mrs. Abraham (mother), 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Corman, Mr. and Mrs. Abraham (parents), 1960-1965 (Box 1)
  - Corman, Leonard (brother), 1955-1970; 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Corman, Doris (sister-in-law), 1958-1969 (Box 1)
  - Corman, Harvey (brother), 1963-1969; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Corman, Sis (sister-in-law), 1966 (Box 2)
  - Artenstein, Sylvia (sister), 1966-1969 (Box 2)
  - Artenstein, Mal (brother-in-law), 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Artenstein, Lisa (niece), 1969 (Box 2)
  - Corman, Andrew (nephew), 1969 (Box 2)
  - Corman, Jed (nephew), 1966-1968 (Box 2)
  - Corman, Polly (niece), 1963-1968 (Box 2)
  - Corman, Richard (nephew), 1966 (Box 2)
  - Corman, Steve (nephew), 1963-1969 (Box 2)
  - Corman, Tony (nephew), 1965; 1969 (Box 2)
- General correspondence
  - Enslin, Ted, 1968-1971 (Box 2)
  - Fang, Achilles, 1950-1968 (Box 2)
  - Gotham Book Mart, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Macfarland, Arthur, 1951-1953; 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Taggart, John, 1970-1971 (Box 2)